<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>DC Metro Area Real Estate Careers and Training Podcast with Kristy Moore</title>
    <link>http://lxrcoaching.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://lxrcoaching.com"/>
    <description>A Podcast about DC Metro Area Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Kristy Moore</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-02-15 11:18:53 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Kristy Moore</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Kristy@LocalExpertRealty.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Kristy Moore</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://lxrcoaching.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Boost your Career with Veteran Real Estate Agent Jason Cadwell</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>A Podcast about DC Metro Area Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Strategies That Will Maximize Your Open House Traffic</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/strategies-that-will-maximize-your-open-house-traffic.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-01 12:52:33 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

In order to maximize your open house traffic, there are several strategies you can use.

Whenever I host an open house, I ascribe to the “land, sea, and air” type of marketing. In other words, I want it advertised online, offline, and anywhere else people can find it.

For example, one way we generate a lot of online traffic online for our open houses is through our event postings on our Facebook page. That way, each event we post shows up in the newsfeed of all our Facebook followers in the area. We also do target marketing through Facebook for people who will most likely purchase a home in that location.

Additionally, we promote the open house on Instagram, other social media websites, and many popular real estate websites (including, of course, the MLS). Don’t forget, if a property isn’t on the market by Wednesday, it won’t show up in the Washington Post’s open house list that week.

One of the offline strategies we use to generate traffic is inviting the neighbors, and there are a couple ways you can do this. The first is simply going door-knocking around the area, handing out flyers, and personally inviting each person you meet.

If you’re short on time, you can do what we call a “neighborhood open house,” where we invite all of the neighbors to the house one hour before the actual public open house. The reason we do this is we want to know who the neighbors are and who the actual buyer prospects are.

I also want to be able to engage with the neighbors on a different level and let them see all the traffic we get. Odds are they want to look at the open house anyway, so they’ll appreciate being invited separately. Every time I’ve done a neighborhood open house, I’ve gotten another listing from that neighborhood.

“Whenever I host an open house, I ascribe to the “land, sea, and air” type of marketing.”

Another tactic we utilize is putting out signs. We put out giant orange signs that you can’t miss if you drive by them, and we set four or five out on each side of any big intersection in the area. We then make a trail of signs leading to the property. I’ve found that for each sign I put out, I get one additional prospect for my open house.

The first thing I ask a person when I meet them at one of our open houses is how they heard about it, because that will give me a good indication of what kind of prospect they are and how far along they are in the buying process. The people who come to an open house because they saw a sign, for instance, generally aren’t as far along in the buying process.

Lastly, you need to do as much as you can to make your open house an event. This is why we refer to our open houses as “grand openings.” Sometimes we even roll out an orange carpet and set up a velvet rope leading up to the entrance. This helps make a spectacle out of it and persuade people to stop by just to see what’s going on.

If you’d like to talk more about how you can generate as much traffic as possible for your open houses or you have any other questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In order to boost your open house traffic, you need to promote it online, offline, and anywhere else people can find it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In order to boost your open house traffic, you need to promote it online, offline, and anywhere else people can find it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dealing With “Sight Unseen” Buyers</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/dealing-with-sight-unseen-buyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-14 15:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Dealing+With+Sight+Unseen+Buyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Sometimes, buyers are relocating and have to buy a home quickly, meaning they don’t have the chance to view a home before purchasing it. So how do you sell a home to a buyer who can’t stop in to see it? Here’s what you need to understand.

You need to be at their beck and call; you must both respond to them and be able look at potential properties quickly. You don’t want to miss any opportunities for your buyer, and you want to get them into a house within their time frame. You’ll likely be dealing with someone in a different time zone, so set up times to talk that work for both of you—you don’t want to be called while you’re asleep and vice versa.

Once you’ve found properties that meet their criteria, show them the property either through a Facetime call or a recorded video. While shooting video, point out both good features and defects—even if the pictures online look great, that may not be the case in person.

You want to talk to buyers about your strategy up front when you’re consulting with them. Explain to them how you’ll handle deficiencies, and educate them on what’s going on in the market. They need to know the moving parts, such as hot/cold markets, multiple offers, negotiation, increased prices, etc. Do this consultation through video chat, or if that’s not available, through phone.

“You don’t want to miss any opportunities for your buyer, and you want to get them into a house within their time frame.”

They will most likely be doing a home inspection without being there. Use an inspector who is well educated on inspection items and specialists who can find additional issues. Shoot a video summary with the inspector, who can tell the buyer directly what’s wrong (or isn’t wrong) with the property. Photos of these problems and a detailed report are also important to share with your buyer. The more you can show, the better. If your buyer has any friends or family in the area, it’s also good for them to provide their opinions on potential homes. 

Another thing to consider about overseas buyers is their cash position. If they’re bringing money, it can get caught up in the treasury or they can have issues getting it released. It’s important that the funds are in the US and are seasoned in their bank account. This is the No. 1 problem we have with overseas buyers—getting their funds from there to here in order to close on time. Let their lender know about this in order to prepare, as well. 

If you have any other questions or need information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to helping you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Dealing+With+Sight+Unseen+Buyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Dealing+With+Sight+Unseen+Buyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are simple ways to manage “sight unseen” buyers. Here’s what I recommend you do.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are simple ways to manage “sight unseen” buyers. Here’s what I recommend you do.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>When Basic Is Better—Tips and Tricks for an Effective Farming Campaign</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/when-basic-is-bettertips-and-tricks-for-an-effective-farming-campaign.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-21 15:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Farms.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The first thing we do after choosing our target market is put together what I call yellow postcards. A yellow postcard is a blank, yellow stock, matte-finish postcard with black writing on it. Why do people fight me on this? Well, they think it’s very boring and basic. But that’s exactly what you want it to be.

If you look at everything in your mail, you’ll notice that it’s all colorful and high-gloss, so a basic yellow postcard actually stands out. Additionally, if it’s not heavily branded, you’re more than likely to get a higher response rate. By that, I mean that you can still have your basic information on it; you do, after all, have to comply with laws and regulations as far as advertising is concerned. But don’t brand your mailers to yourself by putting large photos of your face or company on it. Instead, include a picture of the neighborhood and brand your mailers to the people who live there.

For instance, if you were to mail to “Bryson”, you’d put a picture of Bryson on the postcard and write “Bryson Free Home Market Valuation Report” and also include a blurb about how the recipient is going to receive a bunch of great information on this market report. The domain name will also be branded toward the neighborhood (e.g., www.BrysonPrices.com). Have that URL lead them to a website or landing page that is also branded toward the neighborhood. That way, the prospect is getting information they’re interested in—they’re there for information about their area, not you and all the great things you’ve done.

You’ll also get a lot better contact information this way. If people think they’re going to be harassed by an agent, they’re generally not going to put in the best contact information. Overall, our contact information, including phone numbers and email addresses, is about 90% accurate.

“Prospects want information about their area, not you and all the great things you’ve done.”

So once you’ve chosen your neighborhood(s), have put your postcard together, and created a domain name—all of which are branded to the target area—the best way to send out your mailers is to look up the tax records. Most of the neighborhoods that we farm to have a legal subdivision, so we can actually control our search for addresses within that subdivision.

It is cheaper to do every door directly. However, we have found that it’s not as effective because you can’t target people by their specific neighborhood. People respond to the marketing because it’s directed at their area in every sense, so it’s important to keep that in mind and also not to skimp out in order to save money if you want to get a high return on your investment.

If you have any questions about neighborhood farming or anything else, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Farms.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Farms.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’ll clue you in on what to send and who to send it to when it comes to farming a neighborhood.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’ll clue you in on what to send and who to send it to when it comes to farming a neighborhood.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Build Rapport With Your Clients With This Simple Acronym</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/build-rapport-with-your-clients-with-this-simple-acronym.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Agent Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-07 10:36:39 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Build+Rapport+With+Your+Clients+With+This+Simple+Acronym.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When attending a buyer appointment, it can be difficult to know exactly what to say. While building rapport is the first and most critical step any agent should take during such meetings, it isn’t something that comes easily to everyone. 

Thankfully, we’ve got an easy trick to share with you today that should make this process a little easier. All it takes to become a rapport-building pro is remembering the acronym “FORD.” 

FORD stands for family, occupation, recreation, and dreams—four bread-and-butter topics that are sure to help you jump-start a relationship with any client. 

Each of these topics will be closely tied to clients’ real estate goals, but the first (family) will play an especially significant role in both your initial conversation and their transaction, in general. There are a number of family-related reasons a person may be choosing to move, whether the client has a child on the way and needs more space or is looking to downsize as their college-aged kid prepares to fly the nest. 

The next topic, occupation, will also tell you a lot about a client and their real estate goals—it can shed light on their income, their lifestyle, their commute, and even their personality profile. A teacher with an “S” type personality will be a much different client than an accountant with a “high C” type personality. 

“Knowing who your clients are as people and what they want from their real estate transaction is critical to their (and your) success.”

Third, you should bring the conversation around to the client’s recreational preferences. This will help you suss out whether there are any certain amenities they might like to be near or in their new home, such as a park, swimming pool, gym, or hiking trail. In addition to this, being aware of their hobbies and interests will also help you out when it comes time to give them gifts when following up to gain referral business. 

Finally, don’t forget to ask about their dreams. Some buyers may plan to turn the home they’re purchasing now into an investment property down the line, and some sellers may plan to use the funds from their sale to travel. Knowing what a client’s goals are will help inform the way you treat their transaction. The bottom line is that knowing who your clients are as people and what they want from their real estate transaction is critical to their (and your) success. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Build+Rapport+With+Your+Clients+With+This+Simple+Acronym.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Build+Rapport+With+Your+Clients+With+This+Simple+Acronym.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Building rapport with your clients can be easily achieved if you remember the simple acronym “FORD.”</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Building rapport with your clients can be easily achieved if you remember the simple acronym “FORD.”</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Properly Protect Your Buyer During a Home Inspection</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/how-to-properly-protect-your-buyer-during-a-home-inspection.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Agent Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-21 12:36:28 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+Properly+Protect+Your+Buyer+During+a+Home+Inspection.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’ll be talking about how to protect your buyer during the process of a home inspection. First, the areas of Virginia, Maryland, and Washington D.C. each have some nuances you need to be aware of and understand.

In Virginia, contracts are buyer beware; the seller doesn’t have to disclose anything about the home. The buyer is purchasing the property as-is, and it’s up to the buyer to ensure the home is free from major issues. In Maryland, the seller can disclose everything wrong with the property. However, they can choose not to and instead sign a disclaimer, making the home sale a buyer-beware situation once again.

Don’t settle with just any inspector! You want to avoid the many inspectors out there who simply have a license and don’t know much about construction. You need an inspector who understands construction but also knows when to defer to an expert. Understand that a home inspector is not a specialist, but a generalist. They can tell you something looks wrong, but not exactly what’s wrong with it. For instance, they may tell you that an HVAC system is broken but they won’t be able to tell you why or how to fix it.

“You need an inspector who understands construction but also knows when to defer to an expert.”

Many times, we recommend to buyers that they get multiple inspections. If they’re buying an old house, it’s important to get a plumbing inspection; a lot of these houses have old piping that is corroded and on the verge of bursting. The same goes for having an old HVAC unit inspected; you can always ask the seller to conduct servicing and inspection to make sure it’s in working order. Keep in mind, if the home has a warranty and the HVAC unit is not working at the time of inspection, the warranty company will not cover something that happens afterward because it would then be considered a pre-existing condition. It’s also important to have electrical systems inspected.

With a roof, an inspector won’t usually tell you how much life it has left or even how old it is. If it does seem like it’s old, have an actual roofer inspect it to determine its age and the time it has left. Many people move into properties and have their roofing fail within a few months.

The best thing to do when an inspector finds a red flag is to call in a specialist to provide an expert eye. It may cost your buyer some extra money up front, but it will save them much more in the future.

If you need more information or have any questions, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+Properly+Protect+Your+Buyer+During+a+Home+Inspection.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+Properly+Protect+Your+Buyer+During+a+Home+Inspection.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You don’t want your buyer to end up with a home that’s falling apart. Here’s how to make sure they don’t.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You don’t want your buyer to end up with a home that’s falling apart. Here’s how to make sure they don’t.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Best Way to Convert Proquest Leads Over the Phone?</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/whats-the-best-way-to-convert-proquest-leads-over-the-phone.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Coaching</category>
        
          <category>Phone Call Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-06 13:01:21 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Whats+the+Best+Way+to+Convert+Proquest+Leads+Over+the+Phone%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do you convert Proquest leads over the phone?

Let’s say someone is calling about a property on “123 Main Street” that’s listed at $440,000. If they press 0 to talk to you directly, here’s how you’d answer:

“Hi, this is Kristy with Local Expert Realty. What property can I price for you today?”

The reason why you want to say this is that if you don’t, they’ll hang up on you. They called looking for the price of the property, and if you don’t lead with that, they’ll assume they just got trapped into talking to somebody. Once they tell you about the property they want to know the price for, you’ll say something to the effect of:

“Okay, while I look that up, I know that property is located in Falls Church. Is Falls Church the only area you’re looking in, or are you looking in other areas as well?”

The reason why you want to ask this question is you want to keep the dialogue moving and keep them on the phone while you’re looking up the property’s information and trying to get a feel for whether the caller is a true prospect or not. 

Once you look up the property’s information, tell them about its features and benefits first before listing the price. After that, ask them if that’s the price range they’re looking to buy in. The reason why you want to ask this is that most people call about properties they can’t afford, so you want to know if the property is out of their price range and, again, keep the dialogue moving so they don’t just hang up on you after they learn the price.

“They might claim they’re just curious or brush off their true intentions, but in reality, they’re a prospect.”

At this point, most callers will either tell you they’re only looking in a price range of up to, say, $400,000, or they’re a neighbor who’s just curious what the owners were listing the house at. 

If they’re a buyer who claims $400,000 is their limit, you need to ask whether they’re only interested in the property in question or all of the properties for sale in that area. They’ll most likely respond that they’re interested in all the properties in that area. After that, you can refer to your universal callback script, which we use for all buyers. 

If they’re a neighbor, your next step should be to ask whether they’re looking for an investment property or they wanted to know the price of the home because they’re curious what their own home would sell for. This question will indicate whether they’re a seller prospect or a buyer prospect and tell you which script to proceed with. You can be sure that most neighbors who call about the price of a property are curious what their own home will sell for and will be a seller in the future. They might claim they’re just curious or brush off their true intentions, but in reality, they’re a prospect.

If you have any questions about Proquest leads or there’s anything else I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak to you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Whats+the+Best+Way+to+Convert+Proquest+Leads+Over+the+Phone%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Whats+the+Best+Way+to+Convert+Proquest+Leads+Over+the+Phone%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>To help you convert Proquest leads, here’s an example of a conversation we’d have over the phone with potential prospects.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>To help you convert Proquest leads, here’s an example of a conversation we’d have over the phone with potential prospects.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Everything You Need to Know About Hiring Your First Executive Assistant</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/everything-you-need-to-know-about-hiring-your-first-executive-assistant.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-22 16:55:48 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Everything+You+Need+to+Know+About+Hiring+Your+First+Executive+Assistant.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The first step you should follow before hiring your first executive assistant is to determine what this person will be doing for you on a day-to-day basis. This will help give you a better idea of what your ideal candidate might be like, and, therefore, will help guide your decisions in the hiring process. 

For instance, if you’re looking for someone to assist you in sales, you will be looking for someone with a much different personality than someone who you might hire to assist you with paperwork. I highly recommend that when hiring an executive assistant, you choose someone who can take back-end details and paperwork off of your plate so that you can get out there and make more sales. 

Hiring an executive assistant should ultimately bring you a return. I know this sounds somewhat dry, but it’s true. If you’re going to pay someone an annual salary of $40,000, that person’s assistance should allow you to make an additional $120,000 or so per year. And to make sure this hire is a good investment, you’ll also need to consider how much effort you’ll need to exert to afford to pay them. So while you can hire an executive assistant to allow yourself more freedom, you must also realize that doing so will affect your bottom line. 

Another way to ensure that you’re making the right choice when hiring an executive assistant is by making a list of your own daily tasks and how long each of those tasks take. When you decide which of these tasks would be better off delegated to your future assistant, you’ll be able to form a clear picture of how many hours they’ll be working and what their daily duties will entail. 

As we mentioned earlier, you must also make sure that this person’s personality matches up with the kind of work you’ll expect from them. Someone who will be working with a lot of paperwork will need to be very detail oriented, for example. You can easily assess your candidates’ traits by asking them to complete a DISC profile when they apply. I recommend you use the one found on this website, as this specific assessment will also take the candidates’ values into account. 

“Hiring an executive assistant should ultimately bring you a return.”

All of these considerations are important, but they will only matter if you can actually afford an executive assistant to begin with. Having at least three months’ worth of your future assistant’s pay set aside in savings before you even hire them will safeguard you against potential financial issues that might otherwise arise. This will be especially important if the hire ends up not working out—which, unfortunately, can sometimes happen regardless of the amount of planning you put into the process. 

However, if you consistently check in with their progress, take time to train them each day, and continuously guide them as they become acclimated to their new role, they will be much more likely to succeed.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Everything+You+Need+to+Know+About+Hiring+Your+First+Executive+Assistant.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Everything+You+Need+to+Know+About+Hiring+Your+First+Executive+Assistant.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you interested in hiring an executive assistant? If so, following the steps we’ll be sharing today will be essential in reaching this goal.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you interested in hiring an executive assistant? If so, following the steps we’ll be sharing today will be essential in reaching this goal.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do You Convert “Every Day Open House” Leads?</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/how-do-you-convert-every-day-open-house-leads.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-05 12:12:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Do+You+Convert+Every+Day+Open+House+Leads%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the key to converting an “every day open house” lead? 

Signs that advertise daily open houses and ask buyers to call for times can be a great way to get in touch with potential clients. 

Buyers who reach out after seeing these signs may believe that the times have already been set, but what the signs actually indicate (as you probably know) is that these homes are available to be shown at any time. 

“When buyers ask about when you’ll be holding an open house, simply ask when they’d like to see it.”

And this is exactly what you can tell buyers when they call. When they ask about when you’ll be holding an open house, simply ask when they’d like to see it. After this, the next step is to run through the qualifying questions on your universal call-back script. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call, a text, or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Do+You+Convert+Every+Day+Open+House+Leads%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+Do+You+Convert+Every+Day+Open+House+Leads%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What does it take to convert an “every day open house” lead? Today I’ll explain</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What does it take to convert an “every day open house” lead? Today I’ll explain</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tips on How to Approach a Motivated Seller</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/tips-on-how-to-approach-a-motivated-seller.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-21 13:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Tips+on+How+to+Approach+a+Motivated+Seller.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to talk about how to convert a motivated seller.

What do I mean by a motivated seller? Well, a motivated seller can come from various websites; they come from sites like zBuyer, from the radio, from postcard farming, or other online sources where people are looking to sell their house fast for cash or they’re looking for an investor to buy their house.

The important thing to remember about a motivated seller is their purpose for calling you. Since they typically just want to sell their house fast with little hassle, you don’t want to approach them the same way you’d approach a normal seller. By ‘normal seller,’ I mean someone who is willing to take steps in preparing their house to sell for the most money possible. Those sellers are looking for advice, marketing strategies, and an altogether different type of person than a motivated seller.

I believe in giving people what they want. If a motivated seller wants you to come to their house and make a cash offer, then give them the cash offer.

“It’s really important to understand what their motivation is and the type of property you’re dealing with so you know which way to advise them.”

When they call in, or if you call them back about an online inquiry, make sure that you set the appointment. They’ll ask you questions about what kind of offer you’re going to give them, but you need to be sure to tell them that you can’t give them a price without seeing the house first. Then you can set a date to stop by the house. When you do, give them two options: you can tell them what they’d get if you bought the home for cash with no contingencies, or you can suggest purchasing the home as an investor, where they’d fix up the house and sell it for top dollar.

At this point, if they’re still giving you pushback, they may not be a motivated seller at all; they could just be testing you to see what this is all about and whether it’s a scam or not. It’s important to distinguish between a real prospect and someone who is just looking for information. If they’re serious, they’ll likely set up a time to meet with you.

It’s really important to understand what their motivation is and the type of property you’re dealing with so you know which way to advise them. The great thing is that most real estate companies won’t offer them both options, which gives them some freedom to do one in case the other doesn’t work out.

If you have any questions about converting motivated sellers, please feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Tips+on+How+to+Approach+a+Motivated+Seller.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Tips+on+How+to+Approach+a+Motivated+Seller.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How do you convert a motivated seller? Today I’ll give you some tips to think about.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How do you convert a motivated seller? Today I’ll give you some tips to think about.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Step-by-Step Guide on Converting Property Inquiry Leads</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/a-step-by-step-guide-on-converting-property-inquiry-leads.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-06 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Converting+Leads.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I&rsquo;d like to guide you through the process of converting property inquiry leads. Let&rsquo;s take a look at what this involves.&nbsp;

&nbsp;

Agents often ask me about converting property inquiry leads, like those from Zillow, and today I’d like to provide some insight into this question. 

First of all, keep in mind that property inquiry leads are very different from search leads, pay-per-click leads, etc. Generally, these leads are further along in the process and are strongly focused on seeing the house they reached out to you about. Their main goal is to see the home—not to meet with you, or any other agent. 

Still, there is a way to approach this scenario that will let you and your lead both get what you want. The key is to hook them with their goal when you reach out. To do this, give them a call, introduce yourself, and ask when they’d like to schedule a showing at the house they’ve inquired about. 

After that, you can begin to qualify them. Then, if they’re qualified and not currently working with another agent, you can proceed with guiding them through the rest of the real estate process. 

“Setting up distinct, reasonable expectations from the start will help you and your client clear a path toward home buying success.”

Understanding a lead’s motivation, schedule, and current circumstances will all be essential in successfully converting them. 

When it comes to motivation, leads with a specific reason for moving will be more likely to go through with the transaction. Therefore, narrowing down their motivation will be key. 

In addition to this, also make sure your lead has met with a lender and is working within their budget. This is just one more reason why meeting with leads before taking them on a showing is so important. 

You don’t want a client to fall in love with a home they aren’t qualified for. Setting up distinct, reasonable expectations from the start will help you and your client clear a path toward home buying success.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Converting+Leads.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Converting+Leads.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today, I’d like to guide you through the process of converting property inquiry leads. Let’s take a look at what this involves.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today, I’d like to guide you through the process of converting property inquiry leads. Let’s take a look at what this involves.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What's the Best Landing Page for Free Home Value Reports?</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/whats-the-best-landing-page-for-free-home-value-reports.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-23 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Best+Free+Landing+Page.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re looking for the best landing page for free home value reports, we highly recommend Top Producer’s Market Snapshot. 

This software is inexpensive and highly customizable, so it’s easy to alter landing pages based on the audience you’re trying to reach. Beyond that, it also allows you to track where leads are coming from. 

“Overall, we have found Market Snapshot to be an amazing system for staying in front of prospects.”

Another reason we use Market Snapshot is that it offers robust reports. Market Snapshot’s reports helps clients see neighborhood trends, market conditions, list-to-sale price ratios, and more. 

You also have the freedom to choose how often you’d like to reach out to your clients through Market Snapshot, whether it’s every two weeks or every six months. Overall, we have found Market Snapshot to be an amazing system for staying in front of prospects. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Best+Free+Landing+Page.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Best+Free+Landing+Page.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we’d like to give you a brief overview of why we use Top Producer’s Market Snapshot to create landing pages and stay in front of our prospects.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we’d like to give you a brief overview of why we use Top Producer’s Market Snapshot to create landing pages and stay in front of our prospects.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Help Your Buyer Win Against Multiple Offers</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/how-to-help-your-buyer-win-against-multiple-offers.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-08 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to talk about how you can make sure that your buyer wins in a multiple offer situation. Generally, a buyer is going to compete against anywhere from two to 20 buyers, depending on the property, location, and price. It’s really important to protect your buyer, but it’s also important that you win the deal.

I generally deal with listings and have to deal with multiple offers all the time. Here’s what stands out to me when I’m sifting through offers.

First, stay in communication with the listing agent. I can’t tell you how many times I have buyer’s agents submit offers and never reach out. If a buyer’s agent is reaching out to me and communicating and showing me they are aggressive and a good agent, I’m more apt to stay in communication with them and maybe even give them some hints about how they can win against the other buyers. 

As a seller’s agent, I want to make sure that I’m dealing with a good buyer’s agent because I want to keep things drama-free for my seller and I also don’t want things to fall apart. Stay in communication with the listing agent, show them you won’t cause any drama, and show them that you’re serious.

The next thing you’ll need is a very solid approval letter. Not a pre-approval letter, but a conditional approval letter. This means that your buyer has been through underwriting, has submitted all their documents to the lender, and all the lender needs to authorize the approval is a property. This allows you to shorten financing and appraisal contingencies, and show the seller and their agent that it would be a smooth deal.

“If you use all these strategies, you have a great chance at winning against any other offer.”

Also, have your lender reach out to the listing agent. When I know I’m dealing with multiple offers, this is one way that a buyer and their agent will stand out to myself and my seller. 

The next thing to make sure is that your inspection contingency is very tight with a short deadline and inability to ask for repairs over a certain amount. You could also do a pre-inspection on the property before the offer deadline, then your buyer knows what they are getting into and you can waive the inspection contingency.

The last thing is price. It doesn’t always boil down to price, but you should make sure you have some type of escalation clause in the property that allows your buyer to automatically outbid others until a certain price.

Using all of these strategies, you have a pretty good chance of winning the deal. I get multiple offers on my listing all the time and if an agent comes in with all of the above criteria, they’re generally going to win the home.

If you have any questions about anything I discussed or anything about the real estate business in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+How+to+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I know exactly what listing agents are looking for when they receive multiple offers. Here’s what you need to do to set yourself apart and secure the home for your client.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I know exactly what listing agents are looking for when they receive multiple offers. Here’s what you need to do to set yourself apart and secure the home for your client.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Expert Insight on the Cash Conversion Cycle</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/expert-insight-on-the-cash-conversion-cycle.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-19 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Cash+Conversion+Rate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I have been selling real estate for 12 years, and our team of highly trained professionals, along with our marketing plan, has sold over 700 homes all over the D.C. market. Drawing on this experience, I wanted to discuss the cash conversion cycle and the monetary aspect of having a farm campaign or target market to whom you are actively direct-mailing.

Generally speaking, when you start a new farming campaign, it takes about eight to 12 months to get your investment back. That means if you put $12,000 into it, you will recoup that in about a year. It will take about 18 months after starting to start seeing a return, and up to two years to fully realize your return. The reason for this is that people who are looking for their home value or are interested in getting information about sales in their area are pretty early in the process; about 15% of those people will be looking to do something in the next 90 days, and 85% are looking to do something in more than 90 days.

“When you start a new farming campaign, it takes about eight to 12 months to get your investment back.”

You can generally expect about a 7% to 10% conversion rate, which means that if you get 100 leads, you should be able to close seven to 10 of those within that 18- to 24-month period. As far as your ROI, you should be able to expect an ROI of 5-10X—if you spend $10,000, should be getting $50,000 to $100,000 back.

It will take some time to get your money back. However, once you start to make a return, if you do it consistently, you can make really good returns in the long term. It also depends on who is calling your leads; if you are calling the leads and you are well-scripted and normally high-converting, you will end up at the higher end of the range. If you have an ISA or a newer salesperson calling the leads, you will likely end up at the lower end of the range. This makes sense: if you are doing all the work yourself, you should be getting a higher return, but if you have multiple people involved in the process, you will generally get a lower return, but you should be able to do a higher volume of business.

If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I would love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Cash+Conversion+Rate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Cash+Conversion+Rate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As a 12-year veteran of the real estate industry, I wanted to enlighten you about the cash conversion cycle and give you some insight about when to expect a return on your farming campaign. When you start a campaign, it will take about eight to 12 months to get your investment back, and 18 months to start seeing a return. After two years, your return should be fully realized. To find out why, watch my latest video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As a 12-year veteran of the real estate industry, I wanted to enlighten you about the cash conversion cycle and give you some insight about when to expect a return on your farming campaign. When you start a campaign, it will take about eight to 12 months to get your investment back, and 18 months to start seeing a return. After two years, your return should be fully realized. To find out why, watch my latest video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How and Why You Should Explain the Market to Your Clients</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/how-and-why-you-should-explain-the-market-to-your-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-13 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/Virginia+Real+Estate+Agent+Training+Video-+How+and+Why+You+Should+Explain+the+Market+to+Your+Clients.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the key to explaining our market to buyers and sellers?

When you host buyer or seller presentations, the first thing you should do after building a rapport is to start delving into market data. This will make sure the client you’re working with is properly educated. If a client understands current trends, they will be more receptive to your guidance. 

For instance, imagine you’re in a hot seller’s market with a buyer where properties are selling far above asking price. If your client doesn’t understand this and you advise them to make an offer above list price, they might assume that you’re just trying to achieve a quick transaction. 

When working with buyers, one of the of the first pieces of data you should show them is what the list-to-sold price ratio looks like for the areas they’re interested in. This way, they’ll have a clear idea of what constitutes a good deal and how they should proceed with making an offer. 

“Your clients are more likely to trust your guidance when they understand the reasoning behind it.”

Sellers, too, need to understand market trends. Absorption rates are particularly relevant in their case. This way when your client goes to list their home, they’ll have a clear understanding of how the pricing strategy you choose reflects the market. Being able to guide the seller through your marketing strategy with current trends in mind will make for a more successful transaction, overall. 

Especially when the market is shifting in favor of buyers, you must be able to explain to your sellers why a competitive listing strategy is necessary. Your clients are more likely to trust your guidance when they understand the reasoning behind it. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/Virginia+Real+Estate+Agent+Training+Video-+How+and+Why+You+Should+Explain+the+Market+to+Your+Clients.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/Virginia+Real+Estate+Agent+Training+Video-+How+and+Why+You+Should+Explain+the+Market+to+Your+Clients.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As you’re well aware, market conditions change all the time. And the way real estate professionals strategize their clients’ transactions varies depending on these changes. However, it’s important to imagine how this might seem from a client’s perspective. Today I’d like to discuss the importance of explaining the market to your clients. Whether they are a buyer or seller, your client should know why your plan for their transaction is designed the way it is. To learn more, watch this short video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As you’re well aware, market conditions change all the time. And the way real estate professionals strategize their clients’ transactions varies depending on these changes. However, it’s important to imagine how this might seem from a client’s perspective. Today I’d like to discuss the importance of explaining the market to your clients. Whether they are a buyer or seller, your client should know why your plan for their transaction is designed the way it is. To learn more, watch this short video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Kristy Moore</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Kristy Moore</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">A Podcast about DC Metro Area Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
