<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>DC Metro Area Real Estate Careers and Training Podcast with Kristy Moore</title>
    <link>http://lxrcoaching.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://lxrcoaching.com"/>
    <description>A Podcast about DC Metro Area Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Kristy Moore</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-07-23 10:25:34 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Kristy Moore</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Hire@LocalExpertRealty.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Kristy Moore</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://lxrcoaching.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Boost your Career with Veteran Real Estate Agent Jason Cadwell</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>A Podcast about DC Metro Area Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Expert Insight on the Cash Conversion Cycle</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/expert-insight-on-the-cash-conversion-cycle.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-19 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Cash+Conversion+Rate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I have been selling real estate for 12 years, and our team of highly trained professionals, along with our marketing plan, has sold over 700 homes all over the D.C. market. Drawing on this experience, I wanted to discuss the cash conversion cycle and the monetary aspect of having a farm campaign or target market to whom you are actively direct-mailing.

Generally speaking, when you start a new farming campaign, it takes about eight to 12 months to get your investment back. That means if you put $12,000 into it, you will recoup that in about a year. It will take about 18 months after starting to start seeing a return, and up to two years to fully realize your return. The reason for this is that people who are looking for their home value or are interested in getting information about sales in their area are pretty early in the process; about 15% of those people will be looking to do something in the next 90 days, and 85% are looking to do something in more than 90 days.

“When you start a new farming campaign, it takes about eight to 12 months to get your investment back.”

You can generally expect about a 7% to 10% conversion rate, which means that if you get 100 leads, you should be able to close seven to 10 of those within that 18- to 24-month period. As far as your ROI, you should be able to expect about a 5% to 10% return—if you spend $10,000, should be getting $50,000 to $100,000 back.

It will take some time to get your money back. However, once you start to make a return, if you do it consistently, you can make really good returns in the long term. It also depends on who is calling your leads; if you are calling the leads and you are well-scripted and normally high-converting, you will end up at the higher end of the range. If you have an ISA or a newer salesperson calling the leads, you will likely end up at the lower end of the range. This makes sense: if you are doing all the work yourself, you should be getting a higher return, but if you have multiple people involved in the process, you will generally get a lower return, but you should be able to do a higher volume of business.

If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I would love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Cash+Conversion+Rate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/LXR+Real+Estate+Coaching-+Cash+Conversion+Rate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As a 12-year veteran of the real estate industry, I wanted to enlighten you about the cash conversion cycle and give you some insight about when to expect a return on your farming campaign. When you start a campaign, it will take about eight to 12 months to get your investment back, and 18 months to start seeing a return. After two years, your return should be fully realized. To find out why, watch my latest video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As a 12-year veteran of the real estate industry, I wanted to enlighten you about the cash conversion cycle and give you some insight about when to expect a return on your farming campaign. When you start a campaign, it will take about eight to 12 months to get your investment back, and 18 months to start seeing a return. After two years, your return should be fully realized. To find out why, watch my latest video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How and Why You Should Explain the Market to Your Clients</title>
        <link>http://lxrcoaching.com/how-and-why-you-should-explain-the-market-to-your-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kristy Moore</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-13 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/Virginia+Real+Estate+Agent+Training+Video-+How+and+Why+You+Should+Explain+the+Market+to+Your+Clients.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the key to explaining our market to buyers and sellers?

When you host buyer or seller presentations, the first thing you should do after building a rapport is to start delving into market data. This will make sure the client you’re working with is properly educated. If a client understands current trends, they will be more receptive to your guidance. 

For instance, imagine you’re in a hot seller’s market with a buyer where properties are selling far above asking price. If your client doesn’t understand this and you advise them to make an offer above list price, they might assume that you’re just trying to achieve a quick transaction. 

When working with buyers, one of the of the first pieces of data you should show them is what the list-to-sold price ratio looks like for the areas they’re interested in. This way, they’ll have a clear idea of what constitutes a good deal and how they should proceed with making an offer. 

“Your clients are more likely to trust your guidance when they understand the reasoning behind it.”

Sellers, too, need to understand market trends. Absorption rates are particularly relevant in their case. This way when your client goes to list their home, they’ll have a clear understanding of how the pricing strategy you choose reflects the market. Being able to guide the seller through your marketing strategy with current trends in mind will make for a more successful transaction, overall. 

Especially when the market is shifting in favor of buyers, you must be able to explain to your sellers why a competitive listing strategy is necessary. Your clients are more likely to trust your guidance when they understand the reasoning behind it. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/Virginia+Real+Estate+Agent+Training+Video-+How+and+Why+You+Should+Explain+the+Market+to+Your+Clients.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://lxrcoaching.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kristy+Moore/Virginia+Real+Estate+Agent+Training+Video-+How+and+Why+You+Should+Explain+the+Market+to+Your+Clients.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As you’re well aware, market conditions change all the time. And the way real estate professionals strategize their clients’ transactions varies depending on these changes. However, it’s important to imagine how this might seem from a client’s perspective. Today I’d like to discuss the importance of explaining the market to your clients. Whether they are a buyer or seller, your client should know why your plan for their transaction is designed the way it is. To learn more, watch this short video.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kristy Moore</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As you’re well aware, market conditions change all the time. And the way real estate professionals strategize their clients’ transactions varies depending on these changes. However, it’s important to imagine how this might seem from a client’s perspective. Today I’d like to discuss the importance of explaining the market to your clients. Whether they are a buyer or seller, your client should know why your plan for their transaction is designed the way it is. To learn more, watch this short video.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro Area, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Kristy Moore</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Kristy Moore</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">A Podcast about DC Metro Area Real Estate; It's industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
